when it comes to finance most of us have
the same opinion that it's nothing but a
scary and complicated subject especially
term insurance so today let me simplify
term insurance for you you must have
heard of it but have you considered
buying it hi I'm Monica from pretty much
Finance today I'll be telling you
everything you need to know about term
insurance
why it should be a part of your
investment planning so let's get started
see term insurance is the purest form of
insurance it provides a large sum of
money called a life cover to your loved
ones in case of any unfortunate event in
return you pay a small amount as a
premium at regular intervals term
insurance can be a safety net for your
loved ones in your absence this money
can be used to continue existing
Investments that you've planned for your
family's future it can also be used by
your loved ones to pay off loans so they
won't be burdened with any loan
repayment and their future goals will
not be compromised plus you also get tax
benefits on the premiums paid under
Section ATC the sooner you get term
insured is the better it is because when
you invest at a young age your premiums
are lower it will also provide you and
your loved ones with extended coverage
and Financial Security from an early age
if you start today your premium amount
will be
well to know this check out the ICICI
pro-term insurance calculator the link
is in the description now let us quickly
understand the basics of term insurance
life cover as a thumb rule you should
have a life cover that's 15 to 20 times
your annual income Claims Settlement
ratio it tells you the number of claims
settled by an insurance company in a
year you should always go for a brand
that has a consistent claim settlement
ratio as it assures you that your
family's claim will be settled if time
comes Riders Riders are like add-on
benefits they provide enhanced
protection and can be added to your term
plan at a nominal cost most term plans
offer a rider that provides Financial
Security against critical illnesses like
cancer heart disease kidney disease and
more where the entire claim amount is
paid on diagnosis without any hospital
bills some term plans provide a rider
where future premiums are waived off in
case of an unfortunate event that
affects your ability to work or move
around physically another common rider
provides additional money to your family
in case of death due to an accident
brand this is the most important thing
to keep in mind while buying the term
insurance go for a trusted partner only
which has a legacy of protecting lives
to ensure that your family will be
secured no matter what you can buy a
term plan by contacting your financial
advisor or buy it online in just three
easy steps go to the ICICI Prudential
Life Insurance website and calculate
your premium fill up the application
with your personal and professional
details review your application and make
the payment and it's done so what are
you waiting for go check out term plans
by ICICI Prudential Life by clicking on
the link in description
thank you